Just three months ago, unfortunately, I had an
accident.  Fortunately, nothing happened to me.
However, my car suffered quite a bit of damage.  The
two doors on the right side of my car were
damaged.  And there's a hole in the front door.
Look at the pictures of the car.
In fact, as you can see, I hope you can understand
that the type of car has also been completely
damaged.  I'm
not just telling you the story of this accident.  Because as soon as
this accident happened, I
called my insurance company and
explained the whole thing.  But what
happened next was a terrible experience.
In this video, I will tell you about my experience with insurance claims.  Along
with that, I
will tell you what insurance you should take in 2025.
Let's see what happened after the accident. I
called my insurance company as usual and you can see
how the front door was
damaged and the back door
was also in a repairable condition. The insurance
company said that they will replace the front door
and repair the back door
but not do anything to the tile.
I said okay. I just requested
that the car be repaired at the company's authorized dealership to
which they replied that
I would have to pay the GST at the company's authorized dealership out of my own pocket and that
I have a 100 percent cashless claim policy.
They said that if I get the
car repaired at the dealership of their choice, they would
charge 1200 taka just for the paperwork.  No other charges will be charged.
I said, "Okay, I'll give you
the car, if you want."  And two weeks later
I got a call.  A replacement for that front door could not be found.
And that's why it was
n't repaired.  And when I asked
how long it would take, they said a
month or two, nothing can be said.  At that moment,
I became very angry and
decided to raise the issue.  But
none of the senior officials were
ready to do anything.  So I
decided to reach out to the senior management of Lincoln Insurance Company.
And I also
mentioned Wikipedia quite naturally.  This
opened the company's eyes.  But they still could
n't find a solution.  They remained
steadfast in their stance and finally, after two months,
my car was fixed.  When I
went to pick up my car, the mechanic there
said, "Madam, where are you stuck?"
We deal with all companies and your
insurance is quite common.  I was
literally shocked to hear this.  I make a
living by analyzing insurance.
If I could be wrong,
what about ordinary customers?  So I decided to do a thorough research and
tell you three or four names.
So that you don't end up like me.
You must be wondering what
car insurance I had to have such a bad
experience.  Of course, I wo
n't slander the name of that company.  But that
company will be completely removed from my list.
And I will also tell you which
company I have my policy with now.   Let's go.  Let's
discuss some basics first.  There
are basically two types of car insurance.  Third party and
comprehensive.  Third party means that
third party damage will be covered in the event of an accident.
But damage to your own car will not be covered.
However, comprehensive insurance will
cover both damage to your own vehicle and damage to a third party's vehicle.
You should definitely take out comprehensive insurance.
Although its premium is high, you can
get peace of mind after taking out insurance.
Some add-ons should be taken with this comprehensive insurance.
First comes Return to
Invoice or RTI.  RTI means that
if your car is severely damaged
or stolen, the insurance
company will pay you the original invoice
amount for the car.  Which includes the car's ex-showroom
price, insurance, and [Music] RC.
If you do not take RTI cover,
you will get the IDV of the vehicle in case of major damage.
IDV is the current
market value of the car, which decreases as the car ages.  The
next important add-on is
zero depreciation cover or zero dip
cover.  This can also be called bumper to bumper.
You can get this cover for five years.
This coverage means that
if your car is damaged, the
insurance company will pay you the full
amount of the damage.  Without any allowance for depreciation.  The
next addon is the Consumables addon.
Consumables include nuts, bolts, AC coolant,
ball bearings, grease, etc.
These parts are usually located at the front of the vehicle
and are most affected in case of damage.
This addon is usually very
cheap so I recommend adding this addon.
Then there are other add-ons
such as engine protection, tire
cover, key and lock set replacement.
[Music] These are not very important.  But
if you feel the need,
you can take them.  So
before we look at the best car insurance companies,
let's recap.  The most
important thing is that you must
take out comprehensive car insurance.
Not a third party.  Along with this,
you must take three odds.  Such as
engine protection, tire covers, etc.   It will
depend on your wishes.  So now let's
see which is the best insurance
company of 2025.  First, let's look at the
claim settlement ratio and network
garages of all companies.  Now as a hygiene
filter, I am
removing companies whose network garages are
below 4000.  Because if the network
garage is not nearby, it
becomes a big problem.  You have seen my experience.
Anyway, my old
insurance company is also being
filtered out.  If you
can guess the name of that company [Music]
then Moonbe will guess.  So
after applying this filter, I
only have 10 company names left.
Now we will
look at the ICR or Income Clearance Ratio of these companies.  But
before that, let's understand what ICR is?  And why is
it important?  ICR refers to the
total claims ratio of the total premiums collected by an insurance company in a financial year.  For example, if
a company's income claim ratio
is 88 percent, it means that the insurer
pays out 880 claims for every 100 rupees in premium collected. ICR gives an
idea of ​​the company's financial health.
If the ICR is more than 100%, it
means that the company has
paid out more claims than it has earned. This means that the
insurer's financial health is not that good
and they may be making losses.  If the
ICR is less than 70%, it means the company has
made good profits and for this they may have
rejected many claims or
charged people higher premiums.
So ideally we should
choose a company that has an ICR
between 70 and 100.  Just to be thorough,
we
will compare the data from the last two years to get a clear picture.  Almost
all companies here had ICRs within our desired range.
But
we removed those companies just for hygiene purposes.
Those whose ICR was less than 70 in any year.
Now we have six companies
left.  Now friends, it is
very difficult to choose a company.
Because everyone's needs are different.  [Music]
Of these, I'm going to list my top four favorites.
HDFC Ergo, ICICI Lombard,
SBI and Tata AIG.  And out of these four,
I made the final with ICICI Lumber.
So in the future my car
insurance will be with ICICI.  And
I will
share my experience with you in one of the next videos.  If
you like the video at all,
please let me know.  Best video on car
insurance.  And then our hard
work will be successful.